# System Support – DevOps Engineer PRAGADA VENKATA PRABHAKAR



Taman Melati, Kuala Lumpur, 53100, Malaysia pragadapv@gmail.com | +6011 3939 6939



#### **SUMMARY**

DevOps Engineer with overall 14 years of IT experience and 5+ years specialization in System and Application Support, Configuration, Build and Release Management, Design and develop CI/CD pipeline and Cloud Implementations. Analysis and design, maintenance of client-server and web applications.

Certified AWS Solutions Architect – Associate, aspiring to build highly available, scalable and fault tolerant architectural solutions for clients to help them migrate successfully from current infrastructure (on premise / Virtual / Cloud) to AWS cloud. Confident in Configuring and deploying instances on AWS, Cloud environments and Data centers.

# **EXPERIENCE**

JUNE 2017 - TILL DATE

System Support - DevOps Engineer, ABSEC MALAYSIA SDN BHD

**APRIL 2014 - MAY 2017** 

Systems Engineer, DevOps Initiatives, NSERVTECH (M) SDN. BHD.

**APRIL 2010 - MARCH 2014** 

System Support and Administration, I-SYS SDN. BHD.

**JUNE 2008 – MARCH 2010** 

System Support Engineer, I-SYS SDN. BHD.

**OCTOBER 2004 - MAY 2008** 

**Software Engineer,** DECIMAL POINT SDN. BHD.

**MAY 2003 – SEPTEMBER 2004** 

**Software Engineer, NE TECHNOLOGIES INDIA PVT. LTD.** 

# **EDUCATION**

2000 - 2003

MIT - Master of Information Technology

Manipal Academy of Higher Education(MAHE), Manipal

1997 - 2000

BSc(IT) - Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Acharya Nagarjuna University(ANU), Guntur

# **CERTIFICATION**

**AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate** 

**Amazon Web Services** 

ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

**AXELOS Ltd.** 

# **SKILLS**

**Cloud Technologies - AWS -** EC2, EBS, S3, VPC, RDS, SES, ELB, EMR, ECS, Cloud Front, Cloud Formation, Elastic Cache, Cloud Watch, RedShift, Terraform, Lambda, SNS, Dynamo DB.

Source/Version Control - GIT, GITHUB, SVN, Jenkins, JIRA

**Build and Release - Maven, ANT, Jenkins** 

Infrastructure Automation - Puppet, Chef, Ansible

**Deployment Automation & Orchestration - Jenkins, Ansible** 

**Change Management - BMC Remedy** 

**Team Collaboration - Confluence** 

**Container Concepts – Docker, Kubernetes** 

**Monitoring Tools - Nagios, Splunk, AppDynamics** 

Languages/Scripting - JAVA, C, C++, COBOL, Python, Ruby, XML, Shell, Power shell

Web Servers – OHS, Apache 2.0/2.2/2.4, Apache Tomcat 5.5/6.0/7.0

**Application Servers – WebLogic, WebSphere, JBOSS** 

**Operating Systems - Linux, Unix, Microsoft Windows** 

Databases - Oracle 9i/10g, My SQL, DB2, SQL Server

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ABSEC MALAYSIA SDN BHD

#### **PROJECT PROFILE #1**

Client: eTiQa Insurance and Takaful June 2017 – Till Date

Role: System Support, Configure, Build and Release – DevOps Engineer

Project Title: Etiqa Online Apps (DSP-Direct Sales Portal and CWP-Customer Web Portal)

Direct Sales Portal is Sales funnel for Etiqa for its Insurance and Takaful products like Motor, HOHH(House owner house holder), Life, Health, Travel, etc,. CWP is for Etiqa customers secure Website that enables businesses to share account-specific information with customers such as policy information, invoices, available promotions, product and order information, calendars, etc.

#### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Maintains, monitors, and supports the infrastructure environment and/or facilities.
- Supports multiple systems or applications of medium to high complexity with multiple concurrent users, ensuring control, integrity, and accessibility.
- Develops new alerts and monitoring techniques based on engineering requirements.
- Recommends changes/enhancements for improved systems availability, reliability, and performance.
- Perform Go-Live activities including the execution of the deployment Plans and checklists
- Analyze the existing Projects Build and Release Process and provide the necessary improvements and Automation avoiding repetitive manual tasks.
- Perform Root cause analysis of the issues arise in production.
- Administrate GIT, GIT User Accounts, GitHub Branch creations and Merge activities as per releases.
- Experience in setting up Upstream and Downstream Jobs Jenkins. Worked with Jenkins Pipelines.
- Perform and manage daily and nightly scheduled and unscheduled builds in Jenkins tool and co-ordinate with dev teams for any build failures.
- Handle multiple builds from Development team, create build jobs in Jenkins and perform deployment activities.
- Deploying WARs/EARs (backend) through WebLogic Application Server console.
- Ansible as automation deployment tool for different projects build outputs.
- Support DevOps Environment and maintain its stability so that Development team can quickly and reliably test their new code.
- We use JIRA for task master and project status tracking and ticketing mechanism.
- Experience in creating Docker Containers leveraging existing Linux Containers and AMI's in addition to creating Docker Containers from scratch.
- Conduct Technical knowledge sessions to entire team on new improved process established along with tools exposure.
- Single POC from DevOps Team and actively participate in all Dev, QA and Production deployments.

Environment: Java/J2EE, Ansible, Shell Scripting, GIT, GIT Hub, Jenkins, Docker, RHEL, ANT, Maven, JIRA, Oracle, WebLogic, OHS, OWCS, HPQC.

#### **PROJECT PROFILE #2**

NSERVTECH (M) SDN. BHD.

Client: Fusionware Pvt Ltd.,India June 2016 – May 2017

**Role:** System Support, DevOps Initiatives (Version Control, Build and Release)

**Project Title:** Fusionware Group Systems

#### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Provides L2 Support to multiple systems and applications of medium to high complexity.
- Develops new alerts and monitoring techniques based on engineering requirements.
- Recommends changes/enhancements for improved systems availability, reliability, and performance.
- Coordinates problem resolution among a variety of functional areas and provides subject matter expertise support for diagnosing and resolving problems.
- Recommends and may implement software or hardware changes to rectify problems or address improvement opportunities.
- Worked on GIT and used Source code management client tools GIT Bash, GitHub, GIT GUI.
- Used sub modules in the GIT and educated users working with sub modules in GIT.
- Managed MAVEN project dependencies by creating parent-child relationships between Projects. Jenkins is used as a continuous integration tool for automation of daily process.
- Writing Maven and Ant build tools for application layer modules.
- Experience in setting up Upstream and Downstream Jobs Jenkins. Worked with Jenkins Pipelines.
- Deploying WARs/EARs (backend) through WebLogic Application Server console.
- Release Engineer for a team that involved different development teams and multiple simultaneous software releases.
- Maintaining automated environment using Ansible playbooks.
- Documented all build and release process related items. L2 support for all the build and deploy issues encounter during the build process.
- Deploy JAVA/J2EE applications through WebLogic Application servers.
- Responsible for the development and maintenance of processes and associated scripts/tools for automated build, testing and deployment of the products to various developments.
- Involved in all projects that move to production and work closely with the Data Center, Development, Quality Assurance and Management teams to ensure cross communication and confirmed approval of all production changes.
- Experience working on User admin groups, maintaining account and monitoring system performance using Nagios.
- Involved in setting up JIRA as defect tracking system and configured various work flows, customizations and plug-ins for the JIRA bug/issue tracker.

**Environment:** Java/J2EE, WebLogic, VMware, Nagios, Ansible, JIRA, Jenkins, ANT, Maven, GIT, GitHub, RHEL 6.x.,Oracle.

#### **PROJECT PROFILE #3**

NSERVTECH (M) SDN. BHD.

Client: DST Systems (US) May 2014 – April 2016

Role: Systems Engineer, DevOps Initiatives.

**Project Title:** Total Retirement Accounting Capabilities (TRAC)

TRAC is the pension plan recordkeeping portion of the TA2000 Mutual Fund System. It handles both tax qualified and non-qualified plans. Tax qualified plans are retirement plans established by an employer that meet specific IRS guidelines.

### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Provides system support, seeks technical assistance or escalates problem, when necessary.
- Documents, monitors, reports, and manages the resolution of systemic issues.
- Works with Engineers, Vendors, and Architects when issues appear systemic or cannot be resolved.
- Recommends procedures and controls for problem resolution or creates temporary solutions until permanent solutions can be implemented.
- Monitoring the disk/process/CPU/memory using Nagios.
- Writing the playbooks using Ansible for provisioning servers.
- Creating branches and tags using GitHub.
- Maintain GIT Repositories, Handling Releases and Branching activities for GitHub.
- Handle multiple builds from Development team, create build jobs in Jenkins and perform deployment activities.
- Responsible for taking the source code and compiling using Maven and package it in its distributable format, such as a JAR / WAR /EAR.
- Automate the build Process Using Jenkins jobs.
- Deploying the JAR / WAR / EAR files in Tomcat app server.
- Setup of the code repository using GIT.
- Verify Deployments logs to check for successful deployments.
- Keeping track of Release files for every release.
- Performing deployments to multiple environments.
- Understanding the client environment, Administrating and creating solutions using AWS services, CI/CD, GIT, Dockers.
- Configuring Jenkins job with related Plugins for Testing, Artifactory, and Continuous Deployment to accomplish the complete CI / CD.
- Taking periodic backups of Jenkins job, restoring in case of there is any issue with Jenkins server.
- Remove impediments to allow team to deliver the business objective
- Helped team to complete tasks successfully and on-time and resolved obstacles encountered by team members.

**Environment:** Java/J2EE, Jenkins, MAVEN, Tomcat, Shell Scripts, XML, ANT, Linux, Windows 7, Docker, GIT, GitHub, Nagios.

**Role:** System Support and Administration

Responsible and work with vendors to provide high availability of assigned data center. Continuous improve and deliver high quality of ICT services. Responsible for day to day IT operations of the company such as user management, trouble shooting, help and advice. Maintaining desktop applications, local area networks, IT security and telecommunications.

#### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Strengthening the IT infrastructure through to implementing new technologies.
- Responsible for hardware and software installation, maintenance and repair.
- Executed strategic IT system procurement and supplier evaluation.
- Manage the IT budgets and expenditure on hardware and software.
- Developing & maintaining the company IT systems, software and databases.
- Recommending and implementing improvements and efficiencies.
- Reporting to the IT Director & Chief Executive.
- IT resource planning and budgeting skills.
- Management of server software and associated backup routines.
- Evaluate, test, advise, train and support IT related projects.
- Procurement of IT hardware, software and maintenance products and services.
- Responsible for the recruitment and training of new staff.
- Writing documentation for ICT procedures, security and disaster recovery.
- Maintaining documentation of changes regarding users, functions & systems.
- Managing the internal & hosted network infrastructure including: firewalls, servers, switches and telephony.
- Oversee the development, design, and implementation of new applications and changes to existing computer systems and software packages.
- Assess new computing technologies and the feasibility of system enhancements to determine potential value for the Group.
- Serve as primary contact with outside vendors in the generation of RFPs, bids, contracts, agreements, and other major vendor interactions.

Role: System Support

Collaboratively planned, developed and implemented most aspects of the I-Sys network and business workflow. Designed and implemented IT policies and procedures to protect data, software, and hardware critical to minimizing disruptions in support of mission-critical military operations.

- Communicated and worked with the individual application development groups, DBAs and the Operations.
- Implemented backup and recovery procedure for system and database on Dell servers running on RHEL.
- Monitoring server activity logs, database and log usage, growth and volume status.
- Wrote scripts for automation and information gathering using Python, Bash shell.
- Diagnosed system hardware and software problems using advanced root-cause analysis.
- Installed, configured third party applications, hardened new and existing servers and desktops.
- Converted all systems into trusted systems to comply with STIG.

#### **DECIMAL POINT SDN. BHD.**

OCTOBER 2004 - MAY 2008

Role: Software Engineer

- Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.
- Documents and demonstrates solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code.
- Prepares and installs solutions by determining and designing system specifications, standards, and programming.
- Improves operations by conducting systems analysis; recommending changes in policies and procedures.
- Obtains and licenses software by obtaining required information from vendors; recommending purchases; testing and approving products.
- Updates job knowledge by studying state-of-the-art development tools, programming techniques, and computing equipment; participating in educational opportunities; reading professional publications; maintaining personal networks; participating in professional organizations.
- Protects operations by keeping information confidential.
- Provides information by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing development and service issues
- Accomplishes engineering and organization mission by completing related results as needed.

#### References are available on request